<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-07-23T09:52:20-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Jiwani | Viget Blog 2018</title><subtitle>This is a blog created for my 2018 Viget Internship as their Rails Developer intern. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">More Work</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/seventh/2018/07/20/reset-password.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="More Work" /><published>2018-07-20T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-07-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/seventh/2018/07/20/reset-password</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/seventh/2018/07/20/reset-password.html">&lt;p&gt;Unlike yesterday where I only developed the iOS app for the group project, I actually did a lot of work in terms of the mobile and web app. For the mobile app, I’ve been making enormous strides. Today, I was able to adjust the launch screen to be seamless when the app laods as well as get the header in order. Also, I’ve been able to make it to where if you press the ‘Log in’ button, the Log in modal pops up in the middle of the screen. I know that doesn’t sound like a lot but it took so long to code everything. I know, I know, some people who might read this will say use storyboards. But if you checked out yesterday’s post, I already said I hate storyboards and I will never, ever, ever, ever use it again unless I really have to. In this case, I don’t have to so I won’t use storyboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of the Rails app, I ran into quite a few problems. Peyton implemented the Reset Password modal recently so now it is my turn to go in and do all the backend for that stuff. The first thing I realized was that I had to override the Passwords controller from Devise and I remember from overriding the Sessions and Registrations controller that that was a pain in the butt. Overriding the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;update&lt;/code&gt; action wasn’t too hard as it was pretty straightforward but the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;create&lt;/code&gt; action was a whole new doozy. Devise has it so that when you create a reset password session, you get two tokens. One long one, and one short one. The long one is stored in the database and the short one is emailed to you so you don’t have to click a long link. But a weird thing is is that if you don’t have the right token, Devise STILL leads you to the password edit page which is not what we want. SO, I had to figure out how the heck Devise creates a reset password token and I have to check whether or not that token is in the DB. This took a while because I had to dig through parts of the gem to get the function I wanted. When I was able to, I finally made it so that the user had to use a proper link otherwise the session wouldn’t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next part that I struggled with was writing the tests. Devise doesn’t really keep track of the token and you can’t reproduce the token with the encryption functions they have. So I had to do some research and I came across a gem called &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;email-spec&lt;/code&gt;. This allows me to look at all the emails that have been sent an inspect their body. This wasn’t super hard to implement but one thing I realized is that Devise sends your email immediately, which takes the app a while to process. This isn’t good because RSpec doesn’t give a flying crap about long processes, it just executes the test as fast as possible. This isn’t good because my tests kept failing because it couldn’t find an email being sent but if it WAITED like a half second, it would see the pending email. So I have a hacky solution in place where you can run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sleep(inspection_time: ...)&lt;/code&gt; and it pauses the test for the specified time in seconds. I don’t know if this is the proper way to do this but it was a way I found that worked. I’ll just have to come in on Monday and see the comments on my PR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See ya Monday!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="seventh" /><summary type="html">Unlike yesterday where I only developed the iOS app for the group project, I actually did a lot of work in terms of the mobile and web app. For the mobile app, I’ve been making enormous strides. Today, I was able to adjust the launch screen to be seamless when the app laods as well as get the header in order. Also, I’ve been able to make it to where if you press the ‘Log in’ button, the Log in modal pops up in the middle of the screen. I know that doesn’t sound like a lot but it took so long to code everything. I know, I know, some people who might read this will say use storyboards. But if you checked out yesterday’s post, I already said I hate storyboards and I will never, ever, ever, ever use it again unless I really have to. In this case, I don’t have to so I won’t use storyboards.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Real iOS Dev</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/seventh/2018/07/19/real-ios-dev.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Real iOS Dev" /><published>2018-07-19T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-07-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/seventh/2018/07/19/real-ios-dev</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/seventh/2018/07/19/real-ios-dev.html">&lt;p&gt;Today pretty much consisted of doing one thing: iOS Development. At first, I was going to just try to complete the tutorial from Brian Voong on Let’s Build That App on YouTube but I realized something. After almost watching like 25 30-minute videos of just developing a fake app, I got kind of tired of listening to his voice. At this point, I really want to start developing an app that would be fun like the one for ThisOrThat, and so I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reality, I didn’t do much coding today. I was just really working on the branding and the launch screen of the app. I got the logos and the files I need from Julia so I went ahead and started to create the basic layout. One thing I learned is that there ARE A LOT, A LOT of different app icons you need to put into Xcode. Different meaning different sizes and it definitely was a hassle to keep exporting the same image over and over again at different sizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I learned that you can create the launch screen in a storyboard but you can’t create it programatically. I think Apple did this on purpose because the launch screen is just meant to be static and there isn’t supposed to be any form of functionality whatsoever. Another thing I learned was that STORYBOARDS SUCK!!!! They’re so confusing and constraints are so gosh darn hard to add. It’s not that making the layout in a storyboard is hard, it is just super confusing. There are so many buttons and windows that it really hurts my brain. This is why I’d rather stick to coding it because there are no buttons or extra windows, it’s just my code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s pretty much all I did today! See ya tomorrow!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="seventh" /><summary type="html">Today pretty much consisted of doing one thing: iOS Development. At first, I was going to just try to complete the tutorial from Brian Voong on Let’s Build That App on YouTube but I realized something. After almost watching like 25 30-minute videos of just developing a fake app, I got kind of tired of listening to his voice. At this point, I really want to start developing an app that would be fun like the one for ThisOrThat, and so I did.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Follows and Comments</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/seventh/2018/07/18/follow-comment.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Follows and Comments" /><published>2018-07-18T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-07-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/seventh/2018/07/18/follow-comment</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/seventh/2018/07/18/follow-comment.html">&lt;p&gt;Today was pretty cool! I learned a couple new things while working on the group project!
First, I started to work on the comments feature and I’ll admit, it was pretty difficult at first. What happened was that Peyton didn’t have a form on his frontend template so I had to go in and add one. Then, I tried submitting the form with AJAX and for some reason it just was not working. I was using Javascript to submit the form and I had &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;remote: true&lt;/code&gt; set and the page was still refreshing. So then I looked up why and I saw that because I’m submitting the form with Javascript, the app isn’t sending an AJAX request to the backend. In order to do so, I needed to add some more code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'#form'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;submit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;ajax&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;({&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;//POST, PUT, DELETE, etc,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;attr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'action'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;serialize&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;success&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;){&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// do stuff&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;){&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;//do more stuff&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This script allows you to send an AJAX request to the backend!!
Then, after I finished the comments, I started to work on Follows. The one thing that I learned while working on that is that you can put multiple parameters into a path in order to match the exact route. That probably just made no sense so let me show you. Say you have a route &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/articles/:article_id/follows/:id&lt;/code&gt;. You can specify an exact route with the exact IDs using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;article_follows_path(@article, @follow)&lt;/code&gt;. This method constructs the entire route for you which is sweet!! After I figured that out, completing the feature wasn’t very hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, tomorrow I’m probably going to add Follow specs and after that, we’ll see what I can work on.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="seventh" /><summary type="html">Today was pretty cool! I learned a couple new things while working on the group project! First, I started to work on the comments feature and I’ll admit, it was pretty difficult at first. What happened was that Peyton didn’t have a form on his frontend template so I had to go in and add one. Then, I tried submitting the form with AJAX and for some reason it just was not working. I was using Javascript to submit the form and I had remote: true set and the page was still refreshing. So then I looked up why and I saw that because I’m submitting the form with Javascript, the app isn’t sending an AJAX request to the backend. In order to do so, I needed to add some more code:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wow I’m Dumb</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/seventh/2018/07/17/uneventful.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wow I'm Dumb" /><published>2018-07-17T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-07-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/seventh/2018/07/17/uneventful</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/seventh/2018/07/17/uneventful.html">&lt;p&gt;Today was pretty uneventful. There wasn’t enough FED stuff done for me to go in and do my backend stuff. So today all I did was iOS development. YAY!!!!!!!! Except I’ve been doing the same tutorial for like a week and a half now and honestly I’m kinda getting bored by listening to that guy just ramble on and me trying to follow along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There wasn’t much that I learned either besides what an &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;inputAccessoryView&lt;/code&gt; is and how to build it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I did get caught on one thing. Last week, I was struggling because for some reason, the tap gestures on my images wouldn’t work. I don’t know why they didn’t work but for some reason they just didn’t. Today, I came across the same gosh darn problem. I tried all the ways to fix my problem by refactoring the code, moving definitions elsewhere, etc. It just wasn’t working. So, I decided to give up and finally create an account on Stack Overflow and ask the question. Here is the link if you want it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/51391053/uiimageview-tap-gesture-not-recognizing-user-interaction-is-enabled&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, somebody answered within like 5 minutes and solved my problem. And the solution really made me look stupid. Instead of setting the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;target&lt;/code&gt; of the gesture to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;self&lt;/code&gt; like it’s supposed to be, I accidentally set it to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nil&lt;/code&gt;. What kinda ticks me off the most is how I never caught that error. I was literally staring at my code for like 10 minutes and still didn’t realize it until I used Stack Overflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well that’s it today. Tomorrow imma work on the group project more.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="seventh" /><summary type="html">Today was pretty uneventful. There wasn’t enough FED stuff done for me to go in and do my backend stuff. So today all I did was iOS development. YAY!!!!!!!! Except I’ve been doing the same tutorial for like a week and a half now and honestly I’m kinda getting bored by listening to that guy just ramble on and me trying to follow along.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Group Project Day</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/seventh/2018/07/16/no-ios.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Group Project Day" /><published>2018-07-16T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-07-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/seventh/2018/07/16/no-ios</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/seventh/2018/07/16/no-ios.html">&lt;p&gt;Today was very unsatisfying in some ways. I came in this morning thinking I would be able to finish handling the Create Poll form in a couple hours but it ended up taking the ENTIRE DAY!!!! I didn’t really mind working on the group project all day because in the end, that’s pretty much my job here as an intern and I love to code. But I lowkey was looking forward to be able to continue with the Chat App tutorial so I could finally start working on making the mobile app for the group project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that I did learn when working on this specific feature is to attach a status code to your JSON response back to the browser. For instance, if a user didn’t put the information properly, I responded back with a:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;render&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;json: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;status&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;error&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;other&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;stuff&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;},&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;status: :unprocessable_entity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that’s a 522 status error code and you can replace that status line with any error type you want. This then allows me to bind an ajax error handler to the specific element like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;poll-form&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;on&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;ajax:error&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;status&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;xhr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;whatever&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;here&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah that’s it. Otherwise, the PR is up and ready to be revieeeewwweeeeeeeeeeeeddddddddddddddddd. See ya tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="seventh" /><summary type="html">Today was very unsatisfying in some ways. I came in this morning thinking I would be able to finish handling the Create Poll form in a couple hours but it ended up taking the ENTIRE DAY!!!! I didn’t really mind working on the group project all day because in the end, that’s pretty much my job here as an intern and I love to code. But I lowkey was looking forward to be able to continue with the Chat App tutorial so I could finally start working on making the mobile app for the group project.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Finished Week 6</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sixth/2018/07/13/finished-week-6.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Finished Week 6" /><published>2018-07-13T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-07-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sixth/2018/07/13/finished-week-6</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sixth/2018/07/13/finished-week-6.html">&lt;p&gt;Today wasn’t that bad honestly. I didn’t really work on the group project because I’m still waiting on Peyton’s stuff and no one reviewed my PR that I put up yesterday. That kinda sucks because the PR isn’t that big and it would be nice to be able to finally merge that branch into master so I don’t have to worry about it ever again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead of the group project, I continued following the tutorial on how to create a basic chat app. I surprisingly didn’t run into any problems but now I realized something: This app is getting complex. It’s getting harder to figure out what is where and what does what exactly. All my stuff is organized but there is already so much code that it gets harder to think about how to fix something that may be wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t really learn anything new today besides the history of audio recording (Thanks Riley) and I simply continued developing this mobile app. 
Also, this marks the end of the 6th week of my Viget internship and this is nuts!!!! I can’t beliebe all this time is flying by and I really wish I could stay here longer and get paid to code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cya next week!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="sixth" /><summary type="html">Today wasn’t that bad honestly. I didn’t really work on the group project because I’m still waiting on Peyton’s stuff and no one reviewed my PR that I put up yesterday. That kinda sucks because the PR isn’t that big and it would be nice to be able to finally merge that branch into master so I don’t have to worry about it ever again.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Today Was Difficult</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sixth/2018/07/12/difficult.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Today Was Difficult" /><published>2018-07-12T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-07-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sixth/2018/07/12/difficult</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sixth/2018/07/12/difficult.html">&lt;p&gt;Wow what a day! I had two things I needed to do. One was be able to handle user sessions with the new design because the way Devise does it won’t satisfy the specifications. Devise has it so that when the user makes a POST request, the page refreshes and any error that come up appear on the page after reload. However, we can’t reload the page because the modal will dissapear and the user will be confused. In order to do this, I had to override the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Registrations#Create&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Sessions#Create&lt;/code&gt; methods so that they return a JSON response to the browser. Then, the forms have to make an AJAX POST request to the backend and yeah you could probably take it from there. However, figuring out how to override the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Sessions#Create&lt;/code&gt; method was confusing as heck. Devise uses Warden to authenticate their users and trying to figure out where the code flow goes was hard. After a little while, I figured out that invalid credentials returns an HTTP status error and I figured I could check if there was an error when making a request in order to display the error message to the user. This took 3 hours to figure out and boy was it a doozy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I continued to work on the chat app for iOS using Firebase and that caused a lot of errors. But I also learned a couple new things. One, I learned that API calls are asynchronous methods and are made on a background thread. I didn’t realize this before and I got super frustrated. In order to solve this problem, I learned more about completion handlers and now my code is fixed! There was one part though that was causing a lot of errors and it was where I wanted to retrieve images from the Firebase storage. As I was running my code, I would always get a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;EXC_BAD_ACCESS&lt;/code&gt; error or whatever and I really didn’t understand why. So instead of using what Firebase says to retrieve images, I just used a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;URLSession&lt;/code&gt; in order to get the data from the URL that was given.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well that’s all for today so see ya.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="sixth" /><summary type="html">Wow what a day! I had two things I needed to do. One was be able to handle user sessions with the new design because the way Devise does it won’t satisfy the specifications. Devise has it so that when the user makes a POST request, the page refreshes and any error that come up appear on the page after reload. However, we can’t reload the page because the modal will dissapear and the user will be confused. In order to do this, I had to override the Registrations#Create and Sessions#Create methods so that they return a JSON response to the browser. Then, the forms have to make an AJAX POST request to the backend and yeah you could probably take it from there. However, figuring out how to override the Sessions#Create method was confusing as heck. Devise uses Warden to authenticate their users and trying to figure out where the code flow goes was hard. After a little while, I figured out that invalid credentials returns an HTTP status error and I figured I could check if there was an error when making a request in order to display the error message to the user. This took 3 hours to figure out and boy was it a doozy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Simple Chat App</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sixth/2018/07/11/cool-stuff.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Simple Chat App" /><published>2018-07-11T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-07-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sixth/2018/07/11/cool-stuff</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sixth/2018/07/11/cool-stuff.html">&lt;p&gt;Today I didn’t do much besides start the second iOS tutorial for creating a simple chat app. Don’t take that the wrong way because I spent the entire day doing that and I gotta admit it was pretty fun. The tutorial introduced me to Google Firebase which is actually a really nice way for authenticating users. So if I ever need to have users in my mobile app, Firebase here I come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One new thing I did in this tutorial besides implementing text fields and Firebase was adding gestures. adding Gestures, if I am getting this right, are for elements that are not buttons and you can trigger an event from any element based on any gesture. At first, I had a problem with my code because I defined and added the gesture within the instantiation block. However, I guess you can’t do that anymore with Swift 4 and I had to move the adding and registering the gesture down to where I add the specific view as a subview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s pretty much it so this blog is kinda short. That’s okay maybe I’ll make up for it tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="sixth" /><summary type="html">Today I didn’t do much besides start the second iOS tutorial for creating a simple chat app. Don’t take that the wrong way because I spent the entire day doing that and I gotta admit it was pretty fun. The tutorial introduced me to Google Firebase which is actually a really nice way for authenticating users. So if I ever need to have users in my mobile app, Firebase here I come.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Yay I Fixed It</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sixth/2018/07/10/fixed.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Yay I Fixed It" /><published>2018-07-10T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-07-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sixth/2018/07/10/fixed</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sixth/2018/07/10/fixed.html">&lt;p&gt;So if you read yesterday’s blog post, I said I encountered a problem with the method &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;setValuesWithKeys(dict: Dictionary)&lt;/code&gt;. Today, I finally found the solution to that problem and it was by simply adding &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@objc&lt;/code&gt; in front of the attributes you wanted assigned by the method. This is needed because in Swift 3, I guess every object was kinda treated like an Objective-C object and that it was able to be encoded with values from another source. However, Swift 4 removed that option and now you have to manually tell Swift that I want this object treated as if it was in Objective-C. I don’t understand why there are those differences but oh well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I fixed that problem, I pretty much finished up the AppStore tutorial. Everything pretty much does look like the actual App Store except for a few key things. Now, I am going to work on the chat app using Firebase. Hopefully when I finish that by the end of this week, I have enough experience to start developing on my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was pretty normal so nothing else I need to say. See ya tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="sixth" /><summary type="html">So if you read yesterday’s blog post, I said I encountered a problem with the method setValuesWithKeys(dict: Dictionary). Today, I finally found the solution to that problem and it was by simply adding @objc in front of the attributes you wanted assigned by the method. This is needed because in Swift 3, I guess every object was kinda treated like an Objective-C object and that it was able to be encoded with values from another source. However, Swift 4 removed that option and now you have to manually tell Swift that I want this object treated as if it was in Objective-C. I don’t understand why there are those differences but oh well.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mobile Dev Time</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sixth/2018/07/09/mobile-dev.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mobile Dev Time" /><published>2018-07-09T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-07-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sixth/2018/07/09/mobile-dev</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sixth/2018/07/09/mobile-dev.html">&lt;p&gt;Today it starts! I am using Lets Build That App on YouTube to help me get jumpstarted on iOS development. As I am going through these lessons, slowly but surely, I’ve noticed a few things. One is that Swift is a seamless but complicated language. There are so many components to it and so much to keep track of that it can be a little much sometimes. However, Swift looks really cool and XCode is pretty nice so I’m not complaining a whole lot. Next, I’ve learned that in order to do good mobile dev for iOS, you need to know a LOT of methods. The tutorial I am going through now doesn’t use the GUI to outline the UI but instead hardcodes everything, including the constraints. In order to do so, there are so many fricken methods and some of those methods have enormous names. Like the method name itself is like 30 characters long and I’m thinking to myself, “How the heck am I supposed to remember that…?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did come across a problem that I still haven’t fixed though. Apparently, making API requests and getting the response in a JSON format is more complicated than it seems. I can’t follow the tutorial closely because the dude is using Swift 3 while I am using Swift 4. The two versions vary mostly in that the method names are different and there are a lot of deprecated things. So, I’ve encountered a problem where I get the following error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Cannot&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;subscript&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;value&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Data'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;key&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get this error because apparently the method &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;setValuesWithKeys(dict: NSDictionary)&lt;/code&gt; can’t read the JSON response properly and can’t bind the matching values with the class attributes. This is pissing me off because I can’t use the solution the YouTube video has because it is using Swift 3 and not 4. So now, I have to go ahead and find a solution online which I will do tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of the group project, Devise is confusing. As a group, we’ve decided the sign in/up page will be a modal that pops up on the current page and Devise wasn’t made for that type of manipulation by default. So it took a lot of digging around the gem file to figure out how I could redirect the POST request to an overriden method that signs the user in or creates a new one and returns some data to update specific elements. I got it now but it sure was confusing because of all the methods that Devise uses in order to authenticate or create a new user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all for today, see ya tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="sixth" /><summary type="html">Today it starts! I am using Lets Build That App on YouTube to help me get jumpstarted on iOS development. As I am going through these lessons, slowly but surely, I’ve noticed a few things. One is that Swift is a seamless but complicated language. There are so many components to it and so much to keep track of that it can be a little much sometimes. However, Swift looks really cool and XCode is pretty nice so I’m not complaining a whole lot. Next, I’ve learned that in order to do good mobile dev for iOS, you need to know a LOT of methods. The tutorial I am going through now doesn’t use the GUI to outline the UI but instead hardcodes everything, including the constraints. In order to do so, there are so many fricken methods and some of those methods have enormous names. Like the method name itself is like 30 characters long and I’m thinking to myself, “How the heck am I supposed to remember that…?”</summary></entry></feed>