<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-06-07T17:24:33-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Jiwani | Viget Blog 2018</title><subtitle>This is a blog created for my 2018 Viget Internship as their Rails Developer intern. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">My Blog Looks SWEET!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/first/2018/06/07/damn-ir-looks-good.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Blog Looks SWEET!" /><published>2018-06-07T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-06-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/first/2018/06/07/damn-ir-looks-good</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/first/2018/06/07/damn-ir-looks-good.html">&lt;p&gt;Hey ya’ll I just finished my fourth day at Viget. It was quite an eventful day as I learnt a lot of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I had a meeting with Peyton to discuss how I could better design my blog. He definitely gave me some great pointers which I’ve implemented. Now, the header is Viget blue and the footer is Viget orange. Everything is pretty much Viget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing he did recommend was putting the buttons that are currently on the home page. Despite that being a great idea, holy crap that was hard to implement. Javascript sucks (Sorry REACT devs) and it was pretty frustrating to figure everything out. However, it does seem I’ve got the basic functionality down. There is a weird thing that happens where once I press a button, the fade in and fade out isn’t necessarily smooth. I’m gonna have to ask Prayash about it tomorrow and see if we can fix anything. Also, my JS code is kinda messy so I’m going to also see if there is a way to clean it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, this concludes my blog post.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="first" /><summary type="html">Hey ya’ll I just finished my fourth day at Viget. It was quite an eventful day as I learnt a lot of things.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I figured it out.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/first/2018/06/06/i-figured-it-out.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I figured it out." /><published>2018-06-06T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-06-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/first/2018/06/06/i-figured-it-out</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/first/2018/06/06/i-figured-it-out.html">&lt;p&gt;Well, this is my third day at Viget and everything is going pretty well. Today I had a meeting at 8:30 AM for the Intro to Business Dev and that sucked. Not the content or the people in the meeting, just the fact that I had to pull myself out of bed at 6:00 AM to get to the meeting on time. I don’t really like waking up early because I’m a night owl and not a morning riser but sometimes you gotta do what’s expected of you. It’s all good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After playing around with Jekyll for a little while, I finally have the entire framework down. I know how to override the default layouts given by Jekyll and I figured out how the templating works. Jekyll uses Liquid templating which sounds dumb and horrible and the mathematical operations are absolutely wack. Instead of writing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you have to write&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;modulo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;7&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isn’t that dumb?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welp, that’s it for this post. Cya tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="first" /><summary type="html">Well, this is my third day at Viget and everything is going pretty well. Today I had a meeting at 8:30 AM for the Intro to Business Dev and that sucked. Not the content or the people in the meeting, just the fact that I had to pull myself out of bed at 6:00 AM to get to the meeting on time. I don’t really like waking up early because I’m a night owl and not a morning riser but sometimes you gotta do what’s expected of you. It’s all good.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Second Day at Viget!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/first/2018/06/05/my-second-day.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Second Day at Viget!" /><published>2018-06-05T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-06-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/first/2018/06/05/my-second-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/first/2018/06/05/my-second-day.html">&lt;p&gt;Hey! This is my second day at Viget and it’s going really well so far. 
Today, I had a lot of meetings but it was quite fun. It was nice to be able to 
immerse myself in what a real-life office scenario would look like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Eli gave me an assignment to create this blog so here it is lmao. Honestly, I was a little
afraid that I was not going to be able to understand how Jekyll works because I’ve never heard of it but
I think I got the hang of it. It’s kinda funky and not like an web framework that I’ve ever had to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, my blog looks pretty bland and I hope to be able to work with Peyton on making the design better
with his help in CSS styling. I would if I could but front-end is a pain in my butt and I really don’t want to tinker
with it for hours to make sure all my formatting is correct.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="first" /><summary type="html">Hey! This is my second day at Viget and it’s going really well so far. Today, I had a lot of meetings but it was quite fun. It was nice to be able to immerse myself in what a real-life office scenario would look like.</summary></entry></feed>